蘇珊·悉德爾曼作品
A Susan Seidelman Film
麥當娜 飾演 蘇珊
Madonna as "Susan"
一位美麗的陌生女士，紅頭髮，
綠色的新潮穿戴
"Beautiful stranger,
red hair, green jump suit,...
在華盛頓廣場公園遷狗走過。
...walking dogs
in Washington Square Park."
我忘不了你，給愛一個機會吧。布萊克。
"Can't forget you. Give love a chance.
Blackie."
希望她給他一個機會。
Hope she gives him a chance.
哦，拜託，羅伯塔，這人肯定有點變態。
Oh, Roberta, please!
He must be some kind of a pervert!
-他可能是真心的。
-沒有叫布萊克的是真心的。
- He could be sincere.
- Nobody named Blackie is sincere.
他不能忘了她，他在相思。這就很棒。
He can't forget her, he's in love.
It's great.
你不是正在讀招聘廣告嗎？
Weren't you reading the want ads?
是的，我知道。
只是，好像找不到什麼。
I know, I was.
I just... can't seem to find anything.
不要接受50,000以下的工作。
Don't settle for anything under 50,000.
-嗨，女士們！
-嗨，艾德裡安，你覺得怎麼樣？
- Hi, ladies!
- Hi, Adrian. What do you think?
-羅伯塔，這才是你。
-我其實只想修剪一下。
- (woman) Roberta, the look is you.
- I just really wanted a trim.
不行，這是你的生日禮物。
No, this is your birthday present.
我要給你點不同的東西。
I want give you something different.
艾德裡安，給她點有特點的，不奇怪的…
Give her something different, not weird...
放心吧，她丈夫會喜歡的。
(Adrian)
Don't worry. Her husband'll love it.
-哇，在這兒呢，吉姆的消息。
-啊？
- Wow, here it is! A message from Jim!
- Huh?
不顧一切找蘇珊，決不動搖。
"Desperately seeking Susan.
Keep the faith."
星期二上午10點，巴特利公園，1號通道，相思的吉姆。
"Tuesday 10am. Battery Park,
Gangway one. Love Jim."
-誰是吉姆？
-哦，天啊，就是明天。
- Who's Jim?
- Oh, God, that's tomorrow.
誰是蘇珊？你認識這些人？
Who's Susan? You know these people?
不是。吉姆全國上下的追隨蘇珊。
No. Jim follows Susan
all over the country.
今年一月她在墨西哥城，然後在西雅圖。
Last January she was in Mexico City,
then Seattle.
他們發送來往的消息，這樣他們能聯繫。
They send messages back and forth,
that's how they hook up.
現在他們在紐約。
Now they're in New York.
不顧一切，我喜歡這個詞，太浪漫了。
Desperate. I love that word.
It's so romantic.
我認識的每個人都不顧一切，除了你。
Everybody I know is desperate
except you.
-我是不顧一切的。
-就你？！
- I'm desperate.
- You?!
呃，某種意義上。
Well... sort of.
《迫切》
(# "Urgent" by Junior Walker)
尋找蘇珊\神秘約會\不顧一切找蘇珊
Desperately Seeking Susan
你不害羞
# You're not shy
你總有招數
# You get around
你渴望飛翔
# You wanna fly
從不腳踏實處
# Don't want your feet on the ground
你高高在上
# You stay up
不願下降
# Won't come down
你渴望生活
# You wanna live
在音樂之中暢想
# Wanna move to the sound
把熱情釋放釋放
# Got fire
到你的血脈之中
# In your veins
被鍛造得堅強
# Burning hard
你不會感覺一樣
# Girl, you don't feel the same
你的渴望
# Your desires
那是瘋狂
# Are insane
你不會停下
# You won't stop
除非你再次做它
# Until you do it again
有時我想知道
# Sometimes I wonder
當我看你的眼睛
# As I look in your eyes
也許你會想到
# Maybe you're thinking
另外的傢伙
# Of some other guy
但我從來不知道…
# But I don't ever know...
服務生
Room service!
開著的！
(woman) It's open!
笑一個。
Smile.
- Hi.
你的報紙和龍舌蘭酒。
I got you a newspaper and your tequila.
-謝謝。
-不客氣。
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
-你想放哪？
-這就行。
- Where do you want it?
- That's fine.
別全花在一個地方。
Don't spend it all in one place.
我不會，謝謝。
I won't. Thanks.
編劇
萊奧拉·拜麗斯
Written by
Leora Barish
導演
蘇珊·悉德爾曼
Directed by
Susan Seidelman
吉姆！
Jimmy!
到時間了！
It's about time!
漂亮
Nice!
再見，布魯斯
Bye-bye, Bruce.
還行吧，啊？
It was fun, huh?
電梯鈴聲
(lift bell)
請別關電梯
(woman) Hold the elevator!
就一會兒
(woman) Wait a second!
你屬於我
(# "You Belong To Me" by Carly Simon)
羅伯塔，別讓我吃那些東西，它們太好吃了。
Roberta, don't let me eat these.
They're so good!
嗨，我想我找到一個。
Hey, I think I've found one.
-一個什麼？
-上樓，過來。
- One of what?
- upstairs. Come on.
他正晚上都盯著我。
He's been giving me the eye all night.
他是誰？
-哪個？
- Who is he?
- Who?
-角落裡的，加裡旁邊的
-賴瑞·斯特曼
- In the corner, near Gary.
- Larry Stillman.
-斯特曼醫生
-是教授是醫生？
- Dr Stillman.
- Plastic surgery?
加裡的牙醫。
He's Gary's dentist.
嗯，至少不是哲學博士。
Well, at least he's not a PhD.
-加裡，你朋友呢？
-你認識的，柏裡。
- Gary, who's your friend?
- You know Becky.
哦！賴瑞·斯特曼…
Oh! Larry Stillman...
-我姐姐萊斯莉。
-你好。
- My sister Leslie.
- Hi, how you doin'?
你原來是牙醫…
(Leslie) So you're a dentist...
-鬧鐘聲
-哦，大傢伙，時間到了！
- (watch beeps)
- Oh! Time out, everybody!
我要上電視了。
I've got a 10.58 spot.
-不錯。
-真好。
- Oh, right!
- Great!
我台將會在女皇區有另一階段進展的報道
Rosemary will have another instalment
of Growing up In Queens.
搜索最近搶劫古埃及文物案
The search continues for suspects...
的嫌疑犯的工作繼續進行。
...in the recent robbery
of ancient Egyptian artefacts.
這一時段的新聞就報道到這裡，下一新聞節目在11點。
That and more, next on the news at 11.
嗨，我是加裡的綠洲的加裡。
Hi. I'm Gary from Gary's Oasis.
在我們紐澤西的樣品庫裡，
我們有數以百計的…
In our New Jersey showroom,
we have hundreds of models...
…浴池和浴盆樣品，給您的都是出廠價。
...of whirlpools and hot tubs
at the lowest manufacturer-to-you prices.
快來加裡的綠洲吧
So come on out to Gary's Oasis.
-我們節假日不休息。
-加裡，進來吧。
- We're open seven days a week.
- Hey, Gary. Come on in!
在加裡的綠洲，你會夢想成真。
(TV) At Gary's Oasis
all your fantasizes can come true!
非常好。
(woman) Very good!
它過去了
It's gone for ever.
那快樂的，年輕的，迷人的表情，我所愛的
That funny, young, lost look... I loved.
它一去不復返了
It won't ever come back.
當我告訴你麗貝塔時我已經殺了她
I killed that
when I told you about Rebecca.
你可以在床上帶著耳機看。
You can watch in the bedroom
with the headphones.
我知道。
I know.
加裡，
Gary,...
你是一直記得你的夢想嗎？
...do you ever remember your dreams?
不知道，我從來沒想過
I dunno, I never thought about it.
他們喜歡那個廣告，你覺得呢？
They liked the commercial,
don't you think?
每個人都覺得你很棒。
Everyone thought you were great.
哦，你明天要…
Oh, you're gonna...
…修理我汽車的收音機，是嗎？
...pick up the radio for the car
for me tomorrow, aren't you?
是。
Sure.
哦，別忘了…
Oh, don't forget...
告訴夥計你是我妻子，因為我們
在物主房間裡放了一個燙髮器
Tell the guy you're my wife because we
put a sauna in the owner's apartment...
他會給我們一個好價錢。
...and he's giving us a really great price.
晚安，寶貝
Night, hon.
聽著，別把蛋糕全吃了！
Hey! Don't eat all that cake!
-蘇珊
-嗨
- Susan!
- Hi.
我天，我們都以為你死了！
My God, we all thought you were dead!
沒，不過在紐澤西罷了。
No, just in New Jersey.
鼓聲
(drum roll)
樂隊演奏
(band strikes up)
讓我們聽吧，女士們先生們，
這是藍，傳說中的藍
Let's hear it, ladies and gentlemen,
for lan, the fabulous lan,...
還有他的最愛的助手水晶玻璃！
...and his lovely assistant Crystal!
嗨
(Susan) Hi.
-蘇珊！你去哪了？
-哪都去。
- Susan! Where have you been?
- All over.
-每個人都知道嗎？
-不是。
- Anybody I know?
- No.
一個大西洋城的人
Some guy from Atlantic City.
在他變認真之前很有趣。
It was fun till he started getting serious.
-最近怎麼樣？
-說真的，我真想辭職。
- How's tricks?
- I'm ready to quit this dump. I really am.
雷不讓我帶眼鏡…
Ray won't let me wear my glasses,...
所以當我不能配合時藍就大怒。
...then lan gets pissed off
when I can't do the tricks.
我是說，我真的看不見啊！
I mean, I'm only legally blind!
我可以理解，如果我把眼鏡戴在乳房上…
I could understand
if I wore my glasses on my tits,...
…那就不會有人看我的臉了。
...but nobody here looks at my face!
拜託，離開這地方吧。
Come on, let's just get outta here.
-我必須去做那只消失的藍鳥。
-聽起來不錯。
- I have to do the Disappearing Bluebird.
- Sounds great.
-你不能等等？
-我真的累了。
- Can't you wait?
- I'm really tired.
我可以叫一些皮薩在家中等你。
I could get some pizza
and meet you at home.
-你找到一個地方了？
-不算是。
- You've got a place?
- Not exactly.
只是我在那裡工作。
But I'm working on it.
哦，不，我知道你要說什麼了。
Oh, no. I know what's coming now.
我保證，就今晚。
Just for tonight, I promise.
求你了。
Come on!
你能保證電話只響七次嗎？
Do you promise
only seven-digit phone calls?
發誓。你不會後悔的。
Cross my heart. You won't regret it.
多謝。
Thanks.
歡迎回來。
Welcome back.
待會兒見。
I'll see you later.
嗨，美人兒，拿一張報紙吧。
Hey, baby. Take a paper.
哇，怎麼這樣。
Wow, I don't believe it.
大西洋城治安環境暴降
暴徒從旅店窗戶上落下
ATLANTIC CITY PLUNGE
MOBSTER FALLS FROM HOTEL WINDOW
靠！
Shit!
鼓聲
(drumming)
打擾！
(man) Excuse me!
-有火嗎？
-沒有，我不抽煙。
- You got a light?
- No, I don't smoke.
蘇珊！
Susan!
你怎麼不對我說一聲再見就離開了？
How come you split
without saying goodbye in person?
每個人見面了都說再見。
Everybody says goodbye in person.
來吧，一起喝一杯。
Come on. Let's go get a drink.
可以，但是只能一會兒。
um, yeah, OK,
but I've only got a few minutes.
-哦，別這樣…
-已經是最後的準備工作。
- Oh, great...
- It's a last-minute thing.
今晚我們在Buffalo做一次演唱會。
The band got this gig in Buffalo
and we start tonight.
下次別在報紙上登廣告了，行嗎？
Next time don't put
an ad in the paper, OK?
蘇珊，我每週都在找你。
Susan, I've been looking for you
for weeks!
陪我去Buffalo吧？
Come to Buffalo with me?
嗯，你可是在工作。
uh-uh, you'll be working.
-無聊的工作
-陪我去吧。
- (Susan) It's boring.
- Come to Buffalo.
我不會讓你閒著無聊的。
(Jim) I'll find some trouble
for you to get into.
我現在已經沒閒心了。
I've had enough trouble already.
你…你和這人睡過？
You... you were with this guy?
我離開時他還活著。
He was breathing when I left.
嗨，你們美女和野獸兩位，
我可不想在橋上出事，快走！
Hey! Beauty and the Beast,
we'll hit traffic on the bridge. Let's fly!
《生之欲》
(# "Lust For Life" by lggy Pop on radio)
我不能就這樣離開你。
I don't like leaving you like this.
-我能照顧好自己。
-好吧。
- I can take care of myself.
- I know.
這樣，我給你一個電話…
Look, I'll give you a number. uh...
有筆嗎？
You got a pen?
好了，這是我朋友迪茲的電話。
All right, this is the number
of my friend Dez.
他人不錯…
He's a great guy...
…如果你有困難了就打給他，他知道怎麼聯繫我。
...and if you really get in a jam, call him.
He'll know how to reach me.
-他有錢嗎？
-別想了，他知道你是什麼人。
- Has he got any money?
- Forget it! He knows all about you.
Johnny Yen又來了，
# Here comes Johnny Yen again
帶著酒和毒品，
# With the liquor and drugs
還有絞肉機
# And the flesh machine
別尋刺激了，好嗎？
No more dead bodies, OK?
我要看看我能幹出什麼來。
I'll see what I can do.
下次我回來還在這裡見面。
Be here next time when I get back.
自從上當後我就沒有好轉…
# And I been hurtin'
since I bought the gimmick...
來吧，寶貝！
Come on, baby!
注意看啊！
(vendor) Check it out!
嗨，寶貝，這太陽鏡專為你準備的。
Hey, baby, I got
a pair of sunglasses just for you!
這帽子再適合你不過了。
This hat'll look great on you, baby.
照照鏡子，好看吧？
Take a look in the mirror.
Beautiful, right?
十美元，便宜吧，十美元。
$10 for the set, all right? Ten bucks.
你買嗎？你哪裡走？
You gonna buy?
Hey, where you goin', babe?
站住！你拿了我的帽子知道嗎？
Yo! Come back!
What are you doin' with my hat?
還給我眼鏡，怎麼回事啊？
Give me my glasses, babe!
What's the matter?
-哦，天，怎麼會這樣！
-對不起。
- Oh, man! I don't believe it!
- I'm sorry.
你在幹什麼？
What are you doin'?
-對不起。
-說句對不起就完了？
- I'm sorry.
- What do you mean, "sorry"? Hey!
抱歉！
Sorry!
《尊嚴》
(# "Respect" by Aretha Franklin
playing in shop)
我不想繼續你的錯誤
# I ain't gonna do you wrong
當你離開
# While you're gone
我不想繼續你的錯誤
# Ain't gonna do you wrong
因為我不想
# Cos I don't wanna
就是你回家時當我問起…
# All I'm askin'
…那一點點尊嚴
# Is for a little respect
when you come home
親愛的，當你回家
# Baby, when you get home
我考慮給你
# I'm about to give you
所有的錢
# All of my money
# And all I'm askin'...
給我個面子吧，不要穿出去。
Do me a favour, baby.
Stay on the carpet, OK?
-挺好看的，是吧？
-是。
- They're great, aren't they?
- I know.
我想要了，但是65美元的價錢有點…
I gotta have 'em, but 65 bucks...
-那是定價。
-別管定價。
- That is the price.
- Forget it.
-我喜歡你這夾克。
-這是Jimi Hendrix（搖滾明星）的。
- I like the jacket.
- It used to belong to Jimi Hendrix.
但我願意用夾克來換靴子。
But I bet he'd love it
if I swapped it for the boots.
成交。
Deal.
# Ooo, your kiss is
# Sweeter than honey
# And guess what?
# So is my money...
很招人喜歡，是吧？
Gorgeous, isn't it?
它曾經可是貓王的。
It used to belong to Elvis Presley.
-試一試嗎？
-行。
- Wanna try it on?
- All right.
# Oh, a little respect
# Oh, hey! A little respect...
我們從雞蛋開始
(TV) We start off with the eggs.
兩個兩個打，動作要快
These go very fast done two by two.
你可以在早晨做
And this you can do in the morning...
然後準備開始做菜。
...and get it all ready for baking.
我會用新方法來做。
I'm gonna bake it and then unmould it.
這有六個雞蛋了。
There are your six eggs.
然後用打蛋器攪拌…
Those get beaten up a little bit
and then in goes...
嗨，羅伯塔
Hello, Roberta.
嗨，朱莉婭
Hello, Julia.
抱歉，主婦們，我不能在家吃晚飯。
Sorry, girls. I can't stay for dinner.
西德的人訂了1500個浴盆
Some guy from West Germany's
got 1500 tubs...
他為人傳統
...he can't get through customs.
我得在鎮上陪他吃飯。
I gotta go have dinner with him in town.
就這一次，我抱歉，你能理解嗎？
It just happened.
I'm sorry. You forgive me?
看起來挺有意思的。
Looks interesting too.
-選好了收音機了嗎？
-收音機？
- Get a good deal on the radio?
- Radio?
-汽車上的。你去城裡幹嘛去了？
-哦，對了，收音機。
- Car radio. You just came from the city.
- Oh, my God, the radio.
-你忘了？
-不是。
- You forgot the radio?
- No!
嗯，對，是，我忘了。
um... Yeah, right, I guess I did.
你可以說你不吃晚飯了，而我卻忙的不可開交。
You could have said
you didn't want dinner. I had to rush!
你忙什麼了？你說你什麼地方都沒去。
You said you didn't go anywhere.
你穿的是什麼？
What are you wearing?
夾克。曾經是Jimi Hendrix的夾克。
A jacket.
It used to belong to Jimi Hendrix.
你買了一個穿過的夾克？
怎麼，我們是窮人嗎？
You bought a used jacket?
What, are we poor?
你這是怎麼啦？
What's going on here?
羅伯塔，我必須要去了。
Roberta, I gotta run! I'm late.
我們晚些再談吧。
We'll talk later, all right?
晚些談。
All right, we'll talk later?
Jimi Hendrix,是嗎？
Jimi Hendrix, huh?
落地聲
(clattering)
電視聲
(TV continues)
警方尋找神秘女人
你賣了？
You sold it?
我落下了開儲物櫃的鑰匙！
I had a key that was important.
I got my shit inside a locker.
-我賣了。
-我留下名字和電話。
- I sold it!
- I'll leave you my name and number.
動作好快，陌生人！
Good goin', stranger.
什麼他媽的陌生人？
Well, what fuckin' stranger?!
大型通鋪。這意味著尿褲子。
Festival seating. That means Portosans.
尿褲子就是站著撒尿，我不想站著撒尿。
Portosans means pissing with flies.
I'm not gonna piss with flies.
你們男人可以尿在瓶子裡。
這算什麼？木房子？
You guys can piss in bottles.
What the hell is this? Woodstock?
電話聲
(phone rings)
-放映員
-迪茲，是我，吉姆。
- Projection.
- Dez, it's me. Jim.
等一會兒。
Hold on a second.
哦，我的天啊。
Jesus Christ!
我在Buffalo脫不了身，請你幫個忙，
是關於蘇珊的。
I'm stuck in Buffalo and I need a favour.
It's about Susan.
是這樣，她在大西洋城遇到的一個傢伙
被人從旅店的窗戶上扔了出去。
See, now some guy she met in Atlantic
City got pushed out of a hotel window.
這裡太亂了，我沒聽見。
This sounds wild. I'm sorry I missed it.
迪茲，我沒開玩笑。
This is serious, Dez.
現在，一個署名陌生人的傢伙登出啟事
要在巴特利公園見她
And now some guy's run an ad to meet
her in Battery Park, signed "a stranger".
這有點怪了，你能不能
It sounds weird.
Could you just go down there...
去看一下她安全嗎？
...and make sure she's OK?
吉姆，維多利亞昨晚剛甩了我，
我心情糟透了。
Jim, Victoria split on me last night.
I'm in a shitty mood.
我沒法立刻就變成你的童子軍。
I'm not in the mood for being a boy scout
right now.
拜託了，迪茲，就耽誤你半個小時。
Come on, Dez.
It'll take you half an hour.
-好了沒有？
-馬上就好，一秒鐘就好。
- (man) Come on!
- Give me a chance here. One second.
起哄聲
(booing)
-她在四點去見他。
-四點？那可要差不多一個小時！
- She's got to meet him at 4 o'clock.
- That's in less than an hour!
吉姆，我可是有工作的人！
Jim, I got a job here, you know!
我求你了。
This one favour.
即使我能找到人替我
Even if I could get someone
to fill in for me,...
可我連她長得什麼樣都不知道。
...I don't even know what she looks like.
聽著，你不會找不到她的。
Look, you can't miss her.
她很好看，金髮，還有，中等身材
She's incredibly pretty,
blonde hair, uh... medium height.
還有她穿著綠色的，上面畫著金色的…
And she's got this green and gold jacket...
一個錐形，一隻眼睛在上面，就像鈔票上那樣。
（共濟會標誌）你肯定能找到她。
...with a pyramid with an eye on top
like a dollar bill. You can't miss it.
-好吧，你要請我吃飯啊。
-行，多謝，我一定請你。
- All right, you owe me one.
- Great. Thanks, Dez, I appreciate it.
好的，再見。
OK, yeah. Bye.
我一輩子都在紐約。
I lived in New York all my life.
我們老去中餐館，意餐館
We used to have Chinese restaurants,
ltalian restaurants.
現在你去吃壽司。所有人都吃壽司。
Now you have these sushi restaurants.
Everyone goes for sushi.
壽司，我討厭這東西。
Sushi... I hate the stuff.
我跟你說，儘管我有一天我買了一些，
Although, I tell you,
I had some the other day.
回家做了，還不錯的，味道像魚。
I took it home, I cooked it, it wasn't bad.
It tasted like fish.
鼓聲
(drumming)
9塊2.
$9.20.
給，不用找了。
Here, keep the change.
哇，這是什麼？嗨，女士！
Whoa! Hey! What is that? Hey, lady!
嗨，女士！
Hey! Hey, lady!
這算什麼？
What is this?
靠，刁民！
Oh, that's cute!
嗨
Hi.
我以前好像見過你。
You look like I've seen you
somewhere before.
-不，我想不是。
-我想是。
- No, I don't think so.
- Yeah, I think so.
-你現在在做什麼事情嗎？
-我在等人。
- You doin' anything right now?
- I'm waiting for someone.
-跟我走，小姐。
-你不明白，我必須去見一個人。
- Come with me, miss.
- I have to meet someone.
-我們談談出租車裡的事情。
-她那裡有我所有的東西。
- We'll talk about it in the car.
- She's got all my stuff.
她會給你他媽的打車費。
She'll give you the goddamn cab fare!
我也不想這樣，可我也得生活。
(driver) I don't need this aggravation.
I work for a living.
想吃霸王餐，我知道法律。
Theft of services. I know the law.
嗨，打擾了，你喜歡吃糖嗎？
Well, hi!
Excuse me, but do you like candy?
-我這有甜甜糖。
-不，謝謝。
- I got some Sugar Babies.
- No, thank you.
我久想談一談，我認識你在大西洋城的的男朋友。
I wanted to have a chat. I was very close
to your boyfriend in Atlantic City.
-不可能，我結婚了。
-我不這樣想。
- No, no, no. I'm married.
- No, I don't think so!
蘇珊？
Susan!
你有一對他給你的漂亮的耳環嗎？
Did you wear the pretty earrings
he gave you?
-我們得談談，我的車就在附近。
-放開我！
- Let's have a chat. My car is over there.
- Let go of me!
-蘇珊。
-讓我走。
- Susan!
- Let go!
-羅伯塔尖叫
-蘇珊！
- (Roberta screams)
- Susan!
蘇珊？
(Dez) Susan?
蘇珊
Susan?
-發生什麼了？
-你怎麼樣？
- What happened?
- Are you OK?
我頭疼。
My head hurts.
我是迪茲，吉姆的朋友。
I'm Dez. I'm a friend of Jim's.
吉姆？
Jim?
你男友吉姆。和你爭吵的那人是誰？
Your boyfriend Jim.
Who was the guy hassling you?
-誰？
-剛剛跑掉的那人。
- Guy?
- The guy that just ran off.
-我不知道。
-你不知道？
- I dunno.
- You don't know?
-我不記得了。
-你記不起來了？
- I don't remember.
- You don't remember?
你還好嗎？
Are you OK?
要不要去醫院？
Do you wanna see a doctor?
-我還好。
-你還可以。
- I'm OK.
- You're OK.
她還好，散了吧。
She's OK. Show's over.
他跟我來的，她還好。
She's with me, she's OK.
要坐下嗎？
Sit down?
你什麼都不記得了嗎？
Do you remember anything?
不知道。
I don't know.
你怎麼到這兒來的？
How did you get here?
不知道。
I don't know.
你記不記得早餐吃得什麼？
Do you remember
what you had for breakfast?
不知道。
I don't know.
你叫蘇珊，記得吧？
You are Susan, aren't you?
-蘇珊？
-不知道。
- Susan?
- You don't know.
好吧，我們這兒有什麼？
All right, what do we have here?
沒錢嗎？
No purse?
你的口袋裡是不是有一些東西？
Do you have anything in your pockets,
maybe?
是什麼？
Is that it?
哦，現在我們得去某個地方。
Ah! Now we're getting someplace.
這是我的電話號碼。
This is my phone number.
是吉姆給你的。
Jim must have given it to you.
這好像似曾相識。
This is like a dejavu.
你怎麼能似曾相識？
你什麼都記不起來了。
How can you have a dejavu
if you don't remember anything?
不不，我是說，一切都是似曾相識的。
No, no. I mean... this is all dejavu.
這是Port Authority儲物櫃的鑰匙。
This is a Port Authority locker key.
我來告訴你吧，我要帶著你趕緊去
Port Authority的儲物櫃。
I tell you what. I'm gonna
run you up to the Port Authority.
也許儲物櫃裡有什麼東西
可以讓你想起來什麼。
Maybe what's ever in the locker will
help you snap out of it. How's that?
-好的。
- OK.
走吧。
Let's go.
等一下。
Wait a minute.
你不是在哄我玩吧？
This isn't some sort of trick, is it?
-你什麼意思？
-我是說，我聽說過你的一些事。
- What do you mean?
- I mean I know a little bit about you, OK?
所以別玩我，因為我心情不好。
So don't even consider jerking me around
because I'm not in a great mood today.
行，我是說，我不會…
Sure, I mean, I wouldn't...
玩你。
...jerk you around.
我都不認識你。
I don't even know you.
你戴上這個。
You better wear this.
但願裡面是一些好東西。
I hope it's filled with something good.
這是什麼
Look at this!
你把它塞得夠滿的了。
You sure do move around a lot, huh?
也許是吧。
Yeah, I guess.
這東西應該是耳環，對吧？
So this stuff does look familiar, right?
這完全不可理喻。
Well, it's not completely unfamiliar.
你知道嗎，當我閉上眼睛，我看到一個金字塔。
You know, when I close my eyes
I see a pyramid.
一個金字塔？
A pyramid?
像你夾克上的那個？
Like on your jacket?
對，就是那個。
Oh, yeah. That must be what it is.
至少你沒丟東西。你好點了嗎？
At least you got everything.
I hope you're feeling better.
-你是不是好點了？
-是。
- You are feeling better?
- Yeah.
很好。那我走了。我得把小摩托換回去。
Good. I gotta go.
I gotta get that scooter back.
那麼，我哪次再來見你？
So, uh... I'll see you around
maybe sometime, huh?
可能我和吉姆一塊來。
Maybe, uh... I'll see you with Jim.
好嗎？保重，再見。
OK? All right, take care! Bye.
拜。
Bye.
蘇珊。
Susan!
你今晚有地方睡覺嗎？
Have you got a place to sleep tonight?
你可以去我那裡。
You can sleep at my place.
就一晚上，沙發上。
One night... on the couch.
但是別給我找事。
But I don't want any drama.
也別叫你的狐朋狗友來。
I don't want your friends coming over.
也別隨便拿走什麼東西。
And I want nothing disappearing
from my apartment. You got that?
咳嗽
(coughs)
你還是別抽了
Maybe you should quit?
是的。
Maybe.
-多謝！
-客氣。
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
你，出去。
OK, you. You're outta here.
耽誤時間。
It's about time.
怎麼回事。
I don't believe it.
抱歉，耽誤你了嗎？
Sorry, man. Have you been waiting?
-下次沒機會了。
-你要明白，這事緊急情況。
- Never ever again!
- Listen, man, it was an emergency.
我明白，沒機會了，下回別管我借了。
I understand. Never ever.
Don't ever ask me again.
-好吧。
-不好意思。
- OK.
- Sorry.
這邊。
This way.
-這有人住？
-當然有人住。
- People live here?
- Yes, people live here!
抱歉，只不過我想這裡有點不一樣。
I just thought it was sort of unusual,
that's all.
得上兩層。
Two flights up.
抱歉。
Oh! Sorry.
抱歉，借過。
Oh! Sorry, man. Excuse me.
他們替我宣揚了這兒有人住。
Those look exactly like my speakers.
嘿嘿，等一等。
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Wait a minute.
你在幹什麼？給我那個。
What do you think you're doing?
Give me that.
謝謝。
Thank you.
這兒他媽怎麼了？
What the hell is goin' on here?
笑聲。
(laughter)
不是吧。
I don't believe it.
你要幹什麼？
(man) What you've gotta do is...
不錯啊，維多利亞。
(Dez) That's just great, Victoria.
迪茲，這是我的東西。
It's my stuff, Dez.
那你就來取了？
So you just come and take it.
沒打個電話，也不商量，什麼也沒有
No phone call, no discussion,
no nothing.
-你好嗎？
-還行。
- How you doin'?
- I'm fine.
這樣，我把這些拿到
下面Porsche（德國跑車）上去。
Listen, uh... I'm gonna take
this stuff down to the Porsche.
我敢肯定有些東西是我的。
I believe some of that stuff is mine.
比如應答機，比如Charlie Parker的唱片。
Like the answering machine.
Like the Charlie Parker records.
-行啊，還你。
-謝謝。
- Oh, you can have it. Here.
- Thank you.
我會為其他的東西給你一張支票，好嗎？
I'll send you a cheque for the rest, OK?
支票？行。
A cheque? Great.
-嗨
- Hi.
他是一個好小伙。
He's really a nice guy.
你一定會開心的。
You'll be happy together.
-抱歉。
-沒事。
- Sorry.
- It's OK.
口哨聲。
(Dez whistles)
其實，你可以打掃一下這地方。
You know...
you could do a lot with this place.
這兒很明亮。
There's a lot of light.
靠。
Ah, shit.
你是湊巧和人吵起來了，對嗎？
It happens, right?
應答機。
(answerphone beeps)
嗨，迪茲，是我，吉姆
(answerphone)
Oh, hi, Dez. It's, uh... It's Jim here.
我剛打電話想知道蘇珊怎麼樣了。
I'm just calling to see if Susan's OK.
我在…媽的，我這兒是在哪裡。
I'm calling from, uh...
Oh, shit, I don't know where we are.
只知道是汽車旅館，嘿，這地方叫什麼？
It's some motel... Hey, where are we?
管他啦，這樣吧，我明天打給你。
Anyway, no, look...
I'll call you tomorrow, OK?
多謝你了。
And thanks again for everything.
真夠哥們，謝謝，拜。
You're a pal. Thanks a lot. OK, bye.
看來電話鈴還要響幾次。
That's gotta ring some bells.
-老實說，不是湊巧。
-不是？
- Honestly, no.
- No?
那糟了。
Terrific.
-我要喝一杯，你要點什麼？
-都行。
- I need a drink. Do you want something?
- All right.
你有的，什麼都行，蘋果汁，可樂，梨子酒
Whatever you're having.
Apple juice. Coke. Perrier.
Miller還是Heineken（都是啤酒品牌）
Miller or a Heineken?
-都行。
-到底哪一個？
- All right.
- Which?
第一個。
Either one.
謝謝。
Please.
口哨
(Dez whistles)
搞錯了吧！
(Dez) I don't believe it!
她把冰箱拿走了。
She took the refrigerator.
-警察怎麼說？
-這種情況大多數在24小時內就能找到。
- What did the police say?
- Most of these cases turn up in 24 hours.
你告訴他們那夾克的事了嗎？
還有她的結婚戒指在皂盒上？
Did you tell them about the jacket?
Her wedding ring in the soap dish?
我說了！
I told them!
他們懷疑她只是有什麼事。
They seem to think she's having an affair.
哦，天啊，也許就是有事。
Oh, my God, maybe she is!
真是荒唐，羅伯塔哪來的事！
It's ridiculous.
Roberta is not having an affair!
-她太冷淡了。
-虧你說得出來
- She's much too uptight.
- That is a horrible thing to say.
我看你對和Becky Shuman偷情還挺得意的。
I suppose you're proud of the way you're
running around with Becky Shuman.
我不知道你在說什麼，
總之，我們沒偷情。
I didn't know you knew.
Anyway, we're not running around!
現在不是說閒話的時候！
We're having
a perfectly respectable affair!
-加裡，讓我問你點事。
-什麼？
- Gary, let me ask you something.
- What?
羅伯塔有性高潮嗎？我是說，和你做的時候。
Does Roberta have orgasms?
I mean, did she have them with you?
-高潮？
-你心裡明白，對吧？
- Orgasms?
- You have heard of them, haven't you?
也許因為你不能給她滿足她才走了。
Maybe she left you
because you weren't satisfying her.
萊斯莉，沒人會癡迷於什麼性高潮！
Leslie!
Not everybody is obsessed with orgasms!
-只是有些人…才有的。
-那麼她呢？
- Some people just... have them.
- Did she?
-你和Phil Donshue談論性高潮嗎？
-你個蠢貨！
- Did Phil Donahue discuss orgasms?!
- You are really a pig!
-至少我體驗過。
-體驗過。我也有！
- At least I know about feelings.
- Feelings. I feel! I feel!
你真噁心，跟你爸一樣。怪不得羅伯塔離開你。
You're disgusting. You're just like Daddy!
No wonder Roberta left you.
你說夠了嗎！
Would you stop saying that!
-加裡
-賴瑞
- Gary...
- Larry!
看著不錯。有羅伯塔的消息嗎？
That looks great.
Any word from Roberta yet?
這麼快就搞上了，萊斯莉。
Fast work, Les.
哦，這裡還有一些雞肉。
Oh, let's have some chicken.
賴瑞，那是明天吃的。
The chicken is for tomorrow. Larry!
警察怎麼說？
What did the police say?
出了這麼大的事你們還吃東西！
I can't believe
you're eating during a crisis!
我們夠緊張的了，你還要怎麼樣？
We're nervous!
那你們應該像個正常人那樣去打鎮定劑！
Then take a Valium like a normal person!
她有一口好牙。
She has great teeth.
這就是我為什麼出現在巴特利公園
(Dez)
That's why I showed up at Battery Park.
吉姆說你的一個朋友摔死在
大西洋城的旅館外邊。
Jim said a friend of yours got killed
outside your hotel in Atlantic City.
他擔心壞了。
He was pretty worried.
摔了？
Killed?
殺死了？
Dead?
這也是你的興趣之一，是嗎，蘇珊？
Sort of goes with the territory,
doesn't it, Susan?
也許我知道是誰幹的。
Maybe I know who did it.
我希望我能想起來。
I wish I could remember.
也許就是你殺的。
Maybe you were the killer.
不可能。
No! (laughs)
我想我要躺一會兒
I should probably lay low for while, huh?
好主意。
It might be a wise idea.
你不知道在碼頭的那個人是誰？
You don't know
who the guy at the quay was?
也許是被你拋棄的情人
Maybe a jilted lover?
肯定不是。
I don't think so.
也有可能。
Maybe he was.
你可知道
You know somethin'?
你不完全是我所想的那樣。
You are not at all what I expected.
你也不全是我想的那樣。
You're not quite what I expected either.
薩克斯
(sax ophone)
我怎麼認識的吉姆？我是說…
Just how did I meet Jim? I mean, how...
我怎麼遇到他的？
How did I meet him?
也許這個有幫助。
Maybe it would help.
我想是在那個咖啡店裡。
I think it was at some coffee shop.
那是你工作的第一天，
It was your first day at work.
吉姆大搖大擺的進來。
Jim waltzed in.
你給他帶來吃的，然後把帳單撕了。
You brought his food over
and you ripped up the check.
他個高嗎？我說的是吉姆。
Is he tall? I mean Jim.
中等個頭吧。
He's about medium.
哪種身材？
Is he sort of thin?
哪種，哪種，呃…
Sort of. Sort of, um...
跟我差不多。
...my build.
眼睛是什麼顏色的？
What colour eyes does he have?
藍的。
Blue.
跟你一樣？
Like yours?
抱歉，抱歉。
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
抱歉。
(Roberta whispers) Sorry.
我不知道怎麼回事，只是…
I don't know what happened. I just...
不好意思。
Sorry.
雷聲
(thunder rumbles)
哼哼
(groans)
過來。
Come on.
迪茲
(whispers) Dez!
Dez...
和我一起吃早餐嗎？
Wanna go out to breakfast with me?
早餐
Breakfast?
你怎麼了？穿的有點噁心。
What have you got on?
Some sort of disguise?
-你不喜歡？
-不，只是，呃…
- You don't like it?
- No, it's, uh...
還是迷人的。
...sort of charming.
我請客。
It's my treat.
你要幹嘛？搶銀行？
What did you do? Rob a bank?
我不知道，也許吧。
I don't know. Maybe.
你要到哪裡去？
Where do you wanna go?
看，我在手提箱找到這個。
See, I found this in the suitcase.
Gunny的咖啡店？我知道這地方。
Gunny's Coffee Shop? I know the place.
它在中央大街附近。
It's over on Center Street.
也許我就是在那兒遇見吉姆的。
Maybe that's the place where I met Jim.
-然後？
-然後…
- So?
- So...
然後我們就去那裡
看看是否有人認識我。
So we go there
and see if anybody remembers me.
看得怎麼樣，有熟悉的嗎？
So what do you think?
Anyone look familiar?
還沒有。
No. Not yet.
我在手提箱裡找到這個，你聽說過嗎？
I found this in the suitcase.
You ever hear of it?
魔術俱樂部？是的，在百老匯附近。
The Magic Club? Yeah.
That's that place over on Broadway.
怎麼了？
Why?
我想我應該去那，看看有沒有熟人。
I thought I'd go there
and see if I remember anyone.
-你知道你要點什麼嗎？
-當然。
- You know what you're having?
- Sure.
你要點什麼？
What are you having?
嗯，是你請客，對吧？
Well, it's your treat, right?
是的，我付賬。
(giggles) Yeah, I got money.
我要點…藍莓點心。
I'm gonna have... blueberry blintzes.
很好，我也要那個。
I'll have that too. That sounds good.
你要點什麼？
What can I get you?
呃，一杯咖啡。
Yes, I would like a... coffee...
還有…甜圈餅
...and a, uh... doughnut.
小姐，如果你有空了，就給我們上吃的吧。
Miss! When you get a chance,
could you take our order?
給你可以，她可不行。
You can stay. She's gotta go.
Mick，那個穿夾克的瘋子女孩來了。
Mick, it's that crazy girl with the jacket.
-你，滾！
-你認識我？
- You, out!
- You know me?!
對，別想在這兒吃霸王餐。
Yeah. You won't get a free meal here.
-我有錢，我可以付款。
-我不要你的錢，滾出去。
- I got money, I can pay.
- I don't want your money. Get out.
-我們有錢，怎麼了？
-想想你自己的事吧。
- We got money. What is it?
- Mind your own business.
-這就是我的事，等一下。
-過來，出去。
- This is my business, wait a minute!
- Come on, out!
-嘿，我和他一起的。
-出去，出去。
- Hey, I'm with her.
- Come on, come on.
你幸運去吧，我沒向你逼帳！
You're lucky I don't press charges!
迪茲。
Dez.
你怎麼樣，還好吧？太對不起了。
Are you OK? Are you all right? I'm sorry!
我說的第一條規則就是別給我找事。
Rule number one was no drama.
-記得嗎？
-是的，我知道，抱歉。
- Remember?
- Yes. I know. I'm sorry.
我們走吧。
Let's get out of here.
不好意思。
I'm sorry.
爭吵聲
(man and woman arguing)
你從來不讓我戴眼鏡。
(woman)
You won't even let me wear my glasses!
回去賣T椊去吧，你被解雇了！
(man) Go back to selling T-shirts!
You're fired!
不對，你錯了，藍，是我辭職不幹了。
(shouts) No, you don't, lan, because I quit!
嘿，別在梯子下面！
(Susan) Hey! Not under the ladder!
我的命運絕不可能比這兒更糟糕的了。
敗類人渣！
My luck can't get much worse anyway.
Miserable scumbags!
也許我應該在床上教訓他。
Maybe I should've slept with him.
姐們，有個巫婆偷了我的衣服…
Man, some witch steals my clothes,...
…米克爾被人從旅店窗戶扔了出去，
現在你又被炒了。
...Meeker gets pushed out a hotel window
and now you get fired.
不太糟，但是壞運氣好像抓著你不放。
No offence, but bad luck really seems
to be following you around.
我們現在都清閒了，一起去看個電影吧。
We're both free now.
Let's just go to the movies.
兩場連映的？
A double feature?
來吧。
Come on!
如果你請我吃爆米花的話，電影票就我買了。
I'll pay for the movie
if you pay for the popcorn.
可以，但是，爆米花多少錢？
OK, but listen. How much is popcorn?
-2.50
-行。
- 2.50
- OK.
笑
(giggling)
就是這地方。
This must be the place.
司機，靠邊停吧，就是這兒。
Sir, could you pull over, please?
This is it.
真是不好意思。
I'm sorry about what happened.
-你沒有生氣吧？
-沒。
- Are you sure you're not angry?
- Yeah.
-真的。
-我沒生氣。
- Really?
- I'm not angry.
你真夠哥們。
OK. You're a real pal.
我會告訴吉姆的。
I'll tell Jim.
-拜
- Bye!
- Bye.
夠哥們，我會告訴吉姆…
A real pal. I'll tell Jim...
布利克大街電影院
Bleecker Street Cinema.
你只是別再這樣開除誰！
(man)
You just don't fire someone like that!
我上哪裡去找這麼文靜的女孩去？
Who am I gonna find
at such short notice?
拜託，你認識那麼多女孩。
Come on, Ray. You know lots of girls.
-很多女人都在找工作。
-媽，別打擾我。
- (woman) Plenty of women need work.
- (Ray) Ma! Let me take care of this.
你好。
Hello.
你看見外邊的招工告示了？
You saw the sign outside?
你是在找工作？
Are you looking for a job?
是的，我想我是。
Yeah. Yeah, I think I am.
-她還在想她在找工作。
-不。
- She thinks she's looking for a job.
- No!
我是在找工作，是什麼工作？
I am, I am! What kind of job?
進來吧。
Come on in.
這位是雷。
This is Ray.
-您好。
-這位是雷的媽媽，格蕾妲。
- Hello.
- This is Ray's mom, Gilda.
嗨。
Hi.
-這位是哈雷。
-嗨。
- This is Henry.
- Hi.
您好，哈雷。
Hello, Henry.
還有我，藍。
And I'm lan.
收音機
(radio on)
加裡先生，你還好嗎？
Are you OK, Mr Glass?
還行，謝謝你。晚安，Daisy。
Fine, thank you. Good night, Daisy.
我希望加裡夫人沒事。
I hope you get good news
about Mrs Glass.
謝謝。
Thank you.
你拿這個包去哪？
Where did you get this bag?
它是我的，加裡夫人把它給我了。
It's mine. Mrs Glass give it to me.
把包給我，Daisy。
Give me the bag, Daisy.
-Daisy，把包給我。
-對不起，這包是我的。
- Daisy, give me the bag!
- Sorry, you ain't getting this bag.
-請你給我，我要好好的問問你。
-這包是我的。
- Please, I'm asking you nicely.
- You're not getting this.
《笨蛋主持》
(# "Sucker MCs" by Run DMC
on ghetto blaster)
嘿，我說，你們能挪個地方吃東西嗎？
Hey, guys. Could you, uh...
have your picnic somewhere else?
嘿，你們這些人！
Hey, guys!
好吧，
Right...
小心輕放，行吧？
Just try to be careful, all right?
聽著，我不想捲入家庭糾紛，好嗎。
Listen, I don't get involved
in domestic disputes, OK?
不是糾紛。
There's no dispute.
在她沒有失蹤前時，她穿著一件夾克。
She had the jacket on
when she disappeared.
某種原因上講，這對她很不一樣。
It was very special to her
for some reason.
你真的記不起來她了？
Don't you even remember her?
你也記不起來夾克了？
Don't you remember the jacket?
黑色的，上面還有一個金色的像金字塔的圖形
It was black and gold and it had
a sort of a pyramid thing on it...
就像鈔票上的那樣。
...like on a dollar bill.
記不清了。
Vaguely.
很好，謝謝，你可真會幫忙。
Great. Thanks.
You've been a terrific help.
等等，等等。
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
她也來過這兒找夾克。
She stopped in here
looking for the jacket, too.
也許你們能互相幫助。
Maybe you can help each other.
電話鈴
(phone rings)
蘇珊，接一下電話。
Susan, will you get the phone?
電話鈴
(ringing continues)
蘇珊，電話！
Susan! The phone's ringing!
蘇珊！
Susan!
你好。
Hello?
等下，她在這兒。
Yeah, hold on. She's right here.
-什麼事？
-你的另一個暗戀者。
- What?
- Another one of your secret admirers.
喂？
Hello?
是，你是誰？
Yeah. Who is this?
加裡·格蘭斯？
Gary Glass?
嗯，嗯。
uh-huh.
哦，你就是巫婆的丈夫，我的東西呢？
Oh, so you're the witch's husband.
Where's my stuff?
嗯。
Yeah.
嗯。也許我能幫你。
Well, maybe I could help you.
聽著，今晚10點30到西21世紀街30號去見我。
Listen, meet me tonight at 10.30
at 30, West 21st Street.
我在櫃檯邊的第三個座位等你，聽明白了？
I'll be waiting on the third floor
near the bar. You got that?
好的，再見。
All right, I'll see you there.
-嘿
-稀少的掌聲
- Hey!
- (sparse applause)
晚上好，先生們女士們。
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
歡迎來到魔術俱樂部，
我是主持人，大雷。
Welcome to the Magic Club.
I'm your host, Big Ray.
今晚我們有一系列的好節目，為所有人準備的。
We have a wonderful line-up for you
this evening, for all you people.
你，先生，就是穿紅色襯衫的…
You, sir, the man in the red shirt...
-你從哪來？
-從布蘭克林。
- Where you from?
- (man) I'm from Brooklyn!
我們當中還有誰是從布蘭克林來的嗎？
Do we have anyone else here
from Brooklyn?
好的。為什麼你們兩個不在一個酒吧間裡？
Right here.
Why don't you two share a cab home?
-笑
-真是好觀眾。
- (man laughs)
- This is a great audience.
好的，讓我繼續吧，我要介紹一位…
(Ray) OK, let's get on with it.
Introducing, back from his...
蘇珊，過來。
Susan! Come here!
獨一無二的，舉世無雙的，冉冉新星…
(Ray) The one, the only, the innovator...
從現在開始，我要你
在我們開始前在這兒呆五分鐘。
From now on, I want you here
five minutes before we begin.
記住，我們從鴿子開始。你看起來很漂亮，要微笑。
Remember, we start with the doves.
You look beautiful. Smile.
Davina，今夜女王。
Davina... Queen of the Night!
所以，你們這些可愛的人們，
讓我們歡呼吧，來吧！
So let's hear it
from all you lovely people. Come on!
掌聲
(applause)
歡迎短曲
(band plays fanfare)
咳嗽
(Susan coughs)
口哨
(wolf whistle)
演奏
(band plays)
掌聲
(applause)
薄荷，又長又薄。
(woman) Menthol, extra-long, ultra-thin!
又長又薄哦，老顧客，就不用我說了…
Extra-ultra long and thin!
Regular, unleaded...
鼓掌
(applause)
不要啊。
Please!
下來吧。
(Roberta) Come down!
Davina
(lan) Davina!
鼓聲
(drum roll)
掌聲
(applause)
謝幕。
Bow!
這一個比那一個還差！
This one's worse than the other one!
值得鼓勵，孩子。
Nice try, kid.
給你的，20美元。
Here you go. 20 bucks.
明晚還是這個時間過來。
See you tomorrow night
at the same time.
-你僱傭我了？
-當然僱傭你了。
- You're hiring me?
- Well, of course we are!
謝謝。
Thank you!
把這些拿回家好好練習，好嗎？
Take these guys home and practise,
all right?
還有，蘇珊，多多練習，好嗎？
And, Susan... practise a lot! OK?
-好的。
-很好。
- All right.
- Good.
《入軌》
麥當娜 唱
[歌詞不譯]
(# "Into The Groove" by Madonna)
# Get into the groove
# Boy, you've got to prove
# Your love to me, yeah
# Get up on your feet
# Yeah, step to the beat
# Boy, what will it be?
# Music can be such a revelation
# Dancing around
# You feel the sweet sensation
# We might be lovers
if the rhythm's right
# I hope this feeling never ends tonight
# Only when I'm dancing
can I feel this free
# At night I lock the doors
where no one else can see
# I'm tired of dancing here all by myself
# Tonight I wanna dance
with someone else
# Get into the groove
# Boy, you've got to prove
# Your love to me, yeah
# Get up on your feet
# Yeah, step to the beat
# Boy, what will it be?
# Gonna get to know you
in a special way...
加裡，格蘭斯，是吧？
Gary Glass, right?
是，你怎麼知道？
Yeah, how did you know?
一猜便知。
Wild guess.
-她離你而去，啊？
-是，兩天前。
- She split on you, huh?
- Yeah. Two days ago.
她之前離開過你嗎？
Has she ever split on you before?
沒，當然沒有。
No, of course not.
-她嗑藥嗎？
-嗑藥？羅伯塔？
- Did she do drugs?
- Drugs? Roberta?
她從小連大麻煙都沒吸過。
She's never smoked a joint
in her whole life.
她可能是李堡（紐澤西）最規矩的人。
She's probably
the straightest person in Fort Lee.
你是什麼意思？
What are you driving at?
-你要喝點什麼？
-呃，不，謝謝了。
- Do you want something to drink?
- um... No, thanks.
我在計劃健身，不喝酒，不吃甜的。
I'm on this health programme, you know?
No alcohol, no sugar...
-你要跳舞嗎？
-跳舞？
- Do you wanna dance?
- Dance?
借過，借過。
Excuse me. Excuse me.
# Live out your fantasy
# Here with me
- # Just let the music set you free
- (Gary coughs)
你看了報紙上關於一個叫米克爾的傢伙的事了麼？
Did you read that stuff in the newspaper
about that guy Meeker?
他在大西洋城被人從旅店窗戶上推了下去。
He got pushed out of a hotel window
in Atlantic City.
-沒有，為什麼？
-羅伯塔參加了這次謀殺。
- No, why?
- Roberta's mixed up in it.
羅伯塔？怎麼可能！
Roberta? That's impossible!
真的。她為米克爾的謀殺而圈定了我。
Fact. She's trying to frame me
for Meeker's murder.
誰是米克爾？
Who's Meeker?
是誰？而且他和羅伯塔到底想幹什麼？
Who's Meeker and what does
he have to do with Roberta?
米克爾死前的同夥和羅伯塔，
兩個人一起幹的。
Ex-partner and Roberta
were in on it together.
我想你弄錯了，
I-I think you're mistaken.
羅伯塔在大西洋城不認識什麼人。
Roberta doesn't know anybody
in Atlantic City.
我看見他們在一起了。
I've seen them together!
你看了羅伯塔和別的男人在一起了？誰？
You saw Roberta with another man! Who?
在我來看就像是個油球。
Looks like a real greaseball to me.
你說的我都不信。
I don't believe a word you're saying.
相信我，你想找到你妻子嗎？
Here, trust me. You wanna find your wife?
-使得，當然我要！
-很好，帶我去你家。
- Yeah, of course I do!
- Good. Let's go to your place.
我家？
My place?
借過。
Excuse me.
# Now I know you're mine
打擾。
Excuse me!
先生。
Sir!
有人跟蹤我。
There's someone following me.
求你了，你能…
Please! Could you... Could you...
有個男人，有個男人跟蹤我…
There's a man...
There's a man following me...
你是怎麼進來的？你不能到這裡來。
How do you get in here?
You're not supposed to be in here.
我知道，對不起，先生，能幫我看一看他走了嗎？
I know. I'm sorry, sir,
but could you please see if he's gone?
有個男人跟蹤我，你可以看看他走了嗎？
There's a man following me.
Could you see if he's gone?
-可以。
-謝謝。
- OK.
- Thank you.
你呆在這裡。
You stay here.
Enrique會小心處理的。
Enrique will take care of it.
不錯！
no mal!
不錯。
Yeah.
電視聲
(singing on TV)
# He's hot!
# Your body's hot
# You're always hot, all the time, hot...
# Oh, I'm so hot, oh!
# So hot!
嗨，我是加裡的綠洲的加裡。
（西班牙語）Soy Gary de Gary's Oasis.
在我們紐澤西的樣品庫裡，
我們有數以百計的…
En nuestro local en New Jersey,...
…浴池和浴盆樣品，給您的都是出廠價。
...tenemos cientos de ba ras calientes
a los precios m  bajos.
快來加裡的綠洲吧，
As?que venga a Gary's Oasis,...
我們節假日不休息！
...abierto siete d s a la semana.
-來吧，加裡。
-不，別這樣。
- 鞨ola, Gary!
- No, muchachas. 韜o!
在加裡的綠洲，你會美夢成真。
At Gary's Oasis
all your fantasies can come true!
升降聲
(lift moves)
先生？
Sir?
先生！
Sir!
升降機接近聲
(lift approaches)
出租車！出租車！
(screeches) Taxi! Taxi!
出租車！
Taxi!
喘息聲
(gasps)
尖叫聲
(screams)
-你自己送上門來了。
-等等，我給錢！
- You'll get yourself in a twist.
- Wait! I have money!
我的錢在我的包裡！
I have money in my bag!
耳環，我要耳環。
OK. The earrings, I need them.
什麼耳環？求求你，你搞錯人了。
What earrings?
Look, I'm not who you think. Please.
好了，好了，別重蹈你已故的小情人的覆轍。
All right, all right, avoid the fate
of your late beloved boyfriend.
警笛聲
(police siren)
鴿子聲
(doves coo)
他是拉皮條的？
Was he your pimp?
什麼？
What?
好的，這樣來吧。
All right, play it that way.
起來吧，你只是頭撞了一小下，
你還活著呢。
Come on, you've just got a little bump
on your head. You'll survive it.
你叫什麼？
What's your name?
你不叫無名氏，對吧？
You got a name, don't you?
好吧，到派出所再問她名字。
All right, we'll settle this
at the station house.
-羅伯塔。
-羅伯塔，是個名字。
- Roberta.
- Roberta. That's a name.
你們搞錯了。
I'm not who you think I am.
這些鳥你怎麼用？
How do you use the birds?
你有個好房子，加裡。
Nice place you got here, Gar.
我們都喜歡。
We like it.
挺結實。
Firm.
嗯，是。
Y-Yeah.
那是羅伯塔的。
They're Roberta's.
《社交指南》
"How To Be Your Own Best Friend."
《夫妻指南》
"I'm OK - You're OK."
《性愛指南》
"Dr Ruth's Guide To Good Sex."
這些也是羅伯塔的？
Are these Roberta's, too?
我不知道她在讀這些。
I didn't know she read this stuff.
你知道嗎，加裡，在你我之間，
You know, Gar, between you and me,...
你真的瞭解羅伯塔什麼？
...what do you really know about Roberta?
漂亮的牆紙。
Nice wallpaper.
在你翻她的衣服之前，
Don't you think
you ought to wait for Roberta...
你不覺得你應該等羅伯塔回來嗎？
...before you start taking her clothes?
她欠我一件外套。
She owes me a coat.
-她體重多少？
-羅伯塔？
- What does she weigh?
- Roberta?
105, 110.
我們差不多，非常接近。
We're close. Very close.
-漂亮的浴缸。
-你喜歡？
- Nice tub.
- You like it?
那是，呃，這是我們眾多受大眾喜愛的款項之一。
That's, uh...
It's one of our most popular items.
你可以安裝在所有的浴室裡，
而且會為您的房子增價。
You can install it in any bathroom and it
increases the resale value of your home.
我沒說我要買一個。
I didn't say I wanted to buy one.
是啊，不好意思。
Right. Sorry.
你要知道，我可以習慣這樣的地方。
You know, I could get used
to a place like this.
來點大麻？
Got any pot?
大，大麻，呃…
P-pot. um...
平常我可以弄一些，
usually I keep some around,...
但是，現，現在，我要出去。
...but r-right now I'm out.
你應該明白。
You know how it is.
來一根火柴呢？
How about a match?
好，停。
(man) All right, stop.
臉向前。
Face forward.
笑一笑。
Smile.
左轉
Turn left.
下一個。
Next.
然後你開始想…
And then you start to think,...
這都算什麼呢？
...what's it all about?
一張大照片。你明白嗎？
The big picture, you know what I mean?
我明白，加裡。
Sure I do, Gar.
我是說，那…
I mean, there...
那有比賺錢更好的生活樂趣，對嗎？
There's more to life
than making money, right?
我的意思是，我知道那個，我是說…
I mean, I know that. I mean...
哦，□。
Oh... Mm.
你知道……
You know... You know how...
這一切是如何來源於
在大學時的一個單純的想法？
...all time comes from
a single point in the universe?
-你明白我說的嗎？
-不。
- You know what I mean?
- No.
我丈夫。
My husband.
我們住在李堡。
We live in Fort Lee.
-電話聲。
-那些事情…
- (phone rings)
- There are...
…發生在太陽系很遠的地方…
...things happening in solar systems
so far away...
…我們根本看不見它們。
...that we can't even see them.
笑
(giggling)
我是說，它們…它們在乎什麼？
I mean, what do... what do they care?
它們在乎什麼，即使我是紐澤西的礦泉浴巨擘？
What do they care
if I am the spa king of New Jersey?
喂，加裡的家。
Hello. Glass house.
笑
(Gary giggles)
喂？
(Susan) Hello?
-喂？
-紐澤西礦泉浴的大王。
- Hello?
- Spa king of New Jersey!
笑
(Gary giggles)
礦泉浴大王。
Spa king!
我可以再打給別的人嗎？求你了。
Could I call someone else? Please?
打吧。
Go ahead.
你，那個穿粉芭蕾舞裙的。
All right. You in the pink tutu.
該走了。
Let's go.
見到你真榮幸。
Nice to have met you.
她最好有一個好的解釋。
She better have a good explanation!
你還沒見到她就開始大叫。
You haven't seen her and you're yelling.
我不是。我就是想知道如果她有麻煩了
為什麼不打個電話？
I am not! I am wondering aloud why she
couldn't have called if she was in trouble!
在你做任何蠢事之前先聽聽她是怎麼說的！
Hear her side of it
before you do anything stupid!
格萊斯先生，Sergeant Taskal。坐下吧。
Mr Glass. Sergeant Taskal. Have a seat.
這是我姐姐萊斯莉。
My sister Leslie.
她在昨晚在下東區被逮捕。
She was arrested last night
on the Lower East Side.
她在一座水塔樓下，我馬上把她帶過來。
She's in a holding tank downstairs.
I'll have her brought up.
當我發現照片一樣時，我立刻給你打了電話。
I telephoned you as soon
as I realised the photographs matched up.
嗨，Ronnie，我是Taskal。把格萊斯帶來。
Hey, Ronnie. Taskal here.
Bring up Glass.
我們可以結案了，她丈夫來了。
We're dropping the charges.
Her husband is here.
是的，顯然他還沒接走她。
Well, obviously
he hasn't picked her up yet.
哦，羅伯塔。
(Gary) Oh, Roberta.
讓我看看。
Let me see that.
哦，天啊。
Oh, my God.
格萊斯先生，不久之前有人交了你妻子的保釋金，
她已經被放走了。
Mr Glass, somebody paid your wife's bail
a little while ago and she was released.
你就與她擦肩而過。
You just missed her.
誰，誰交了保釋金？
Who-Who paid her bail?
男朋友，拉皮條的，你知道嗎？
Boyfriend. Pimp. Who knows?
拉皮條的？
Pimp?
我不知道該怎麼謝謝你，迪茲，
真的太不好意思了。
I don't know how to thank you, Dez.
I'm really sorry.
考慮到這是我最後一次幫你，蘇珊，
Consider it my final favour, Susan.
你還真的沒有辜負你的名聲啊。
You are really living up
to your reputation.
看吧，現在已經完事了，迪茲。
See, now, that's just it, Dez.
結束了，我並不是你想的那個人。
That's it! I'm not who you think I am.
-我可不在乎你是誰。。
-不，不，我不是你說的那個意思。
- I don't care who you are.
- No, no, I didn't mean it that way.
這裡真的很難講明白，我不是…
It's really getting complicated here.
I'm not...
噓。呆著別動。
Sssh. Stay right there.
這是怎麼了？
I don't believe it.
天！
(Roberta) God!
我不敢相信維多利亞能這樣做。
I don't believe Victoria would do this.
哦，天啊。
Oh, my God.
也許是昨晚搶我的那個人幹的。
Maybe it was the guy
who grabbed me last night.
什麼？
What?
搶你的那個人？
The guy who grabbed you?
你看，我跟蹤了我，迪茲。
See, he was after me, Dez.
呃，並不是我，他跟蹤蘇珊…
Well, not me exactly.
He was after Susan,...
管她是誰，我不是！
...wherever she is, who I'm not!
他認為她住在這兒，可是那個她不在，
因為我是…
He thinks she's staying here,
which she isn't because I am...
我不想聽！
I don't wanna hear it!
首先，我屁股被人扔在了人行道上。
First of all, I get thrown out
on my ass on the sidewalk.
接著，我不得不支付了200美元的保釋金
把你從看守所裡接出來。
Then I have to fork up $200 bail
to get you out of jail.
現在，我回家了，看到整個地方被撕的稀爛，
而為什麼我還不知道！
Now I come home and the whole place
is torn apart. Why, I don't know!
你要知道，蘇珊，我不想看到這些狗屁事，
真的不想。
You know, I really don't need this shit,
Susan. I really don't.
好。
Fine.
我走。
I'll leave.
哎呦！
Whoops!
你知道嗎，迪茲，我昨天晚上可能會被人殺死了。
You know, I could have been killed
last night, Dez!
我真的怕得要命！
I was really scared!
別想了。
Forget it.
抱歉給你弄得這麼亂。
Sorry about this mess.
我會賠給你，我會給你寄一張支票。
I can pay you back!
I'll send you a cheque.
很好，又一張支票。
Great. Another cheque.
哭
(sobbing)
對不起。
Sorry.
嘿嘿嘿，
Hey, hey, hey.
這麼亂不是最壞的。
This mess isn't so bad.
我曾經開個派對，比著還要糟。
I've had worse parties than this.
笑
(Roberta giggles)
開電視
(turns TV on)
理查德·諾蘭和布魯斯·米克爾是在等待…
Richard Nolan and Bruce Meeker
were released...
…對他們1982年走私活動的定罪判決
提出上述期間被釋放的。
...pending appeal of their 1982
conviction for smuggling.
他們是偷竊現在紐約展出的開羅收藏品中
They are prime suspects in the
disappearance of the Nefertiti earrings...
娜芙兒提提耳環的主要嫌疑人。
...from the Cairo collection
currently on display in New York.
娜芙兒提提？我靠！
Nefertiti? No shit!
這不正常！我剛剛看了一篇文章…
It's not uncommon!
I've just read an article...
…關於一個女人上午在城裡胡作非為，
..about a woman who turned tricks
in the city all morning...
然後在下午回家前又恢復正常。
...and shopped all afternoon
before going home.
她做了好幾年了，而她丈夫卻一點不知道。
She did it for years
before her husband found out about it.
羅伯塔不可能去賣淫，她哪有妓女那樣的性感身材？
這不可能。
Roberta can't be a prostitute. She doesn't
like sex that much. It's impossible.
哦，天啊，我可聽說有五分之四的妓女是同性戀。
Oh, my God. I have heard that four
out of five prostitutes are lesbians.
萊斯莉，如果我妻子是同性戀的話我會知道的。
Leslie, I think that I would know
if my wife was a lesbian.
怎麼知道？連她是妓女你都不知道。
Why?!
You didn't know she was a prostitute.
加裡，我想你要接受這個事實…
Gary, I think you have
got to accept the fact...
就是在你的關係中存在著那些非常不正常的東西。
...that there is something very unusual
going on in your relationship.
蘇珊
(Gary) Susan.
-蘇珊。
-蘇珊是誰？
- Susan!
- Who's Susan?
呃，別想歪了，她是來幫助我找羅伯塔的。
uh... Don't get the wrong idea.
She was helping me find Roberta.
蘇珊。
(Gary) Susan!
Susan!
你在幹什麼？
What are you doing here?
我有好消息和壞消息，你要先聽哪個？
I got good news and bad news.
What do you want first?
-你說過你會走的。
-好的，好消息。
- You said you were going to leave.
- OK, good news.
你妻子不是跟那油球一起的。
Your wife isn't with the greaseball.
蘇珊，我妻子剛在下東區被人接走…
Susan, my wife has just been
picked up on the Lower East Side,...
……跟著她的帶槍的拉皮條老闆跑的！
...escaping from her gun-toting pimp!
他不是拉皮條的。
He's not a pimp.
-他不是拉皮條的。
- He's not a pimp.
壞消息是他有可能會殺了她，因為他認為她是我。
The bad news is he'll probably kill her
cos he thinks she's me.
-什麼？
-你從來沒讀過嗎？
- What?
- Didn't you ever read this?
她的日記。
She kept a diary.
有一些好定西：睡不著。
It's great stuff. "Couldn't sleep."
走進廚房，加裡進來，關了燈。
"Went into kitchen.
Gary came in. Turned on light."
加裡走了，剩下生日蛋糕。
"Gary left. Finished birthday cake."
這有好幾頁。這將是封底了。
沒有人的生活會這樣無趣。
Pages of it. It's gotta be a cover.
Nobody's life could be this boring.
你不該讀這些的，這是私人隱私。
You shouldn't be reading that. It's private.
是啊，這個與她無關，而與我有關，聽聽這個。
Yeah, well, it's not about her.
It's about me. Listen to this.
他又開始找蘇珊了，她從墨西哥州回來晚了。
"He's looking for Susan again.
She's late returning from Mexico."
這是他第五個啟事了。
"This is his fifth ad."
為什麼他如此強烈的想要見她？
她是誰？
"Why does he want to see her so badly?
Who is she?"
還有我的一張照片。
And there's my picture.
加裡，為什麼你不告訴我她讀了這些啟事呢？
Gary, why didn't you tell me
she read the personals?
我們昨天就可以搞定了。
We could've settled this yesterday.
她一直都在看這些啟事。我不認為…
She read them all the time. I didn't think...
嗯，是。幸虧了每一個人，
我才能活下來想做點什麼。
Yeah, well, fortunately for everybody,
I'm here and I'm thinking.
把車鑰匙給我。
Give me the car keys.
我會把它完整帶回來的。
I'll bring it right back.
嘿咻。
Hiya.
加裡。她拿的是你的汽車鑰匙。
Gary! She is taking the car keys!
別說了，萊斯莉，行嗎？
Shut up, Leslie. OK?
日記本。有點偷偷摸摸的感覺。
她是怎麼評論我的？
Diary. That little sneak,
what did she say about me?
瘋狂尋找
陌生人尋找蘇珊
"Desperately seeking
stranger seeking Susan."
敬啟者，在星期六晚9點半，百老匯魔術俱樂部見。
"Regarding key. Meet me Saturday night,
Magic Club, Broadway. 9.30pm. Be there."
-就這些了？
-她會喜歡的。
- Is that it?
- She'll love it.
去櫃檯付錢。
Pay at the cashier.
四十歲單身白人男性，
尋找下午的玩伴。
"Single white male, 40,
looking for afternoon playmates."
就這些了？去櫃檯付錢。
Is that it? Pay at the cashier.
迪茲…
Dez...
我不是蘇珊。
I'm not Susan.
我是家庭主婦，住在紐澤西李堡。
I'm a housewife
and I live in Fort Lee, New Jersey.
我已經結婚四年了。
I've been married for four years.
我丈夫加裡…
My husband Gary...
他做浴盆和浴室的生意。
He sells bathroom spas and saunas.
你怎麼還是這樣？
You never stop, do you?
不，這是真的，真的。
No, really! Really!
這就是我喜歡你的原因，我從不知道你
下一句會說什麼，過來。
That's why I like you. I never know
what you'll say next. Come here.
-門鎖聲
-迪茲。
- (door lock rattles)
- Dez.
-那是什麼？
-不知道。
- What is that?
- I dunno.
有人想進來。
Someone's trying to get in.
哦，天啊。
Oh, my God.
哦，是吉姆。
Oh, my God, it's Jim.
天啊。
Oh, my God.
吉姆，吉姆。
Jim... Jim. Jim.
謝天謝地，你嚇壞我了。你覺得怎麼樣，啊？
Thank God. You had me worried.
How you doing, man? Huh? Huh?
有人打我了，一片黑。
Somebody jumped me. It was dark.
嗯，呃…
Yeah. uh...
是我幹的。
It was me.
我以為你是別人呢。
I thought you were somebody else.
你以為我是誰？
Who did you think I was?
有人跟蹤了蘇珊，我想你可能是他。
Somebody's been following Susan.
I thought maybe you were him.
誰跟蹤她？
Who's following her?
不知道。
I don't know.
你知道蘇珊。
You know Susan.
從她那裡得到一個清楚的答案真是困難。
It's really tough
to get a straight answer out of her.
她需要我，迪茲。
She needs me, Dez.
我想或許她準備安頓下來了。
I think maybe she's ready to settle down.
安頓下來？蘇珊？別扯了，吉姆。
Settle down? Susan? Come on, Jim!
她從沒有做過什麼安頓的事，
她不是那類人。
She'd never do that.
She's really not the type.
從什麼時候你這麼瞭解她？
Since when do you know her so well?
呃，我只是不能看見她安頓下來。
我是說，她太野性了。
Well, I just can't see her settling down.
I mean, she's too wild.
但是這也是她的魅力。
But that's what's so great about her.
是這樣嗎？
Is that so?
我是說，你真的好像對她做了一番檢查。
I mean, you really seem
to have examined this.
嗯，我們一起度過了一些時間。
Well, we've been spending
some time together.
可…你在說什麼呀，迪茲？
Just... what are you saying here, Dez?
啊？
Huh?
我不想對你胡說八道，吉姆。
I'm not gonna bullshit you, Jim.
是一件不好出口的事，
我沒說它沒有。
It was a shitty thing to do.
I'm not saying it wasn't.
但是你自己說她誘人的。
But you yourself said she was irresistible.
哦，不會吧。
Oh, man.
你，你為什麼不再打我一下，就像這樣的，
把我結果了？
W-why don't you just hit me again
and, like, finish me off?
-你看…
-啊？
- Look...
- Huh?!
別哭喊了。我真的為她而瘋狂…
Don't cry about it.
I'm really crazy about her...
…而且她也為我而瘋狂。
...and she's really crazy about me.
-我對不起，
-聽著，我瞭解蘇珊。
- I'm sorry.
- Listen. I know Susan.
無論她告訴什麼都是胡扯。
Whatever she told you doesn't mean shit.
她不是認真的，迪茲。我是知道的，
我追了她好幾年了。
She plays with people, Dez. I oughta
know, I've been chasing her for years.
我認為她跟我是認真的。
I don't think she's playing with me.
胡說。
Bullshit.
這樣吧，吉姆。
All right, Jim.
我們幹嘛不問問她呢？
Why don't we just ask her?
蘇珊。
Susan!
蘇…她在這兒？
Su...! You mean she's here?!
蘇珊。
Susan!
-到這兒來。
-蘇珊。
- Come on out here.
- Susan...!
蘇珊。
Susan!
她走了。
She's gone.
她就在這兒。
She was here.
我發誓。
I swear to God.
水壺鳴響
(kettle whistles)
迪茲，你在上面嗎？
(Jim) Dez, are you up there?
怎麼了？
Yeah?
猜猜怎麼了？
我想她把我倆都耍了。
Guess what, man?
I think she's jerking us both around.
你什麼意思？
What do you mean?
你看看吧，這個他媽的陌生人是誰？
Check this out.
I mean, who the hell is this stranger?
鼓
(drum roll)
蘇珊，我還是不明白我們來這兒幹什麼。
Susan, I still don't understand
why we're here.
信我吧，加裡。你會驚喜萬分的。
Trust me, Gar.
You're in for a real surprise.
你的驚喜萬分已經讓我緊張了。
Your surprises are beginning
to make me nervous.
-她怎麼說？
-我們會驚喜萬分的。
- What'd she say?
- We're in for a real surprise.
我想我們在這兒看不到Tony Bennett。
I guess we're not gonna see
Tony Bennett here.
我應該叫警察跟著我們。
I'd settle for a police escort.
你怎麼能讓她穿上羅伯塔的夾克？
How could you let her wear
Roberta's jacket?
嘿，她沒衣服了，總得穿點什麼吧。
Hey, she's cold.
She's gotta wear something.
為什麼你不把你的指甲剪了？
(dummy) Why don't you
cut your fingernails?
我聽不見你在說啥…
I can't hear what you're saying...
摀住叫喊
(muffled shouting)
迪茲，如果她看到我們倆都在這兒，
她很可能又一走了之。
Dez, if she sees us both here,
she'll probably just split again.
那你回去吧。
You could go home.
我要看看他媽的陌生人是誰。
I wanna see who this fuckin' stranger is.
讓我猜。三倍龍舌蘭到天亮。
Let me guess. Triple tequila sunrise.
姜味汽水。
Ginger ale.
你是威士忌。
And you're the Scotch.
這是你的。
This must be yours.
朗姆酒和Tab。
Rum and Tab.
坐著別動，我去找找陌生人。
Sit tight. I'm gonna
go look for the stranger.
什麼陌生人？
What stranger?
-天，她可真迷人。
-一坨漂亮的屎罷了。
- God, she's gorgeous.
- Beauty feces.
她在那。
There she is.
-哪？
-就在那兒，和買煙女說話的那個。
- Where?
- Right there. Talking to the cigarette girl.
那不是蘇珊。我之前從沒見過那個女孩。
That's not Susan.
I never even seen that girl before.
迪茲，那是蘇珊。你認為我能搞錯嗎？
Dez, that's Susan.
Don't you think I should know?
那可能是蘇珊，但不是我的蘇珊。
That might be a Susan
but that's not my Susan.
-那是我的蘇珊。
-那麼在巴特利公園的女孩是誰？
- That's my Susan.
- Then who was the girl at Battery Park?
誰是陌生人？
So who's the stranger?
吉米！
Jimmy!
誰是陌生人？
Who's the stranger?
-說來話長。
-嗯啊。
- It's a long story.
- uh-huh.
你怎麼也不會知道她的。
You wouldn't know her anyway.
-她？
-是，她。
- Her?
- Yeah. Her.
過來，找個私人空間去說話。
Come on. We'll talk about it in private.
敲門
(knocking)
我們還有三分鐘上場。
We've got three minutes before curtain!
戴上你的假髮馬上出發。
Get your wig on and get out there!
我在想蘇珊會不會出事。
I wonder what happened to Susan.
看起來像是你丟了女友。
Looks like you lost your girlfriend.
嘿，賴瑞，我結婚了，懂嗎？
Hey, Larry! I'm married, all right?
-哦，得了吧。
-怎麼？
- Oh, please!
- What?
樂隊聲
(band plays fanfare)
晚上好，女士們先生們。
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
歡迎來到魔術俱樂部，我是主持人，雷。
Welcome to the Magic Club.
I'm your host, Ray...
酒吧生，給我結帳吧。
Bartender...
Can I have the check, please?
有誰從女皇區出來的嗎？
Hey, is there anyone out here
from, uh... Queens?
你。好的。我自己是從正常人家的肚子裡出來的。
You. Well, I'm from
normal parents myself.
零星笑聲
(scattered laughter)
是這樣的，今晚我們給大家一個特別的待遇。
Anyway, we got a special treat
for you people this evening.
讓我介紹一下獨一無二的，舉世無雙的…
Introducing the one, the only...
蘇珊，快上來。
Susan, get up here!
…還有他可愛的助手，Davina…
...and his very lovely assistant, Davina...
…今夜女王，鼓掌吧。
...Queen of the Night! So let's hear it!
加裡，那是…
(Leslie) Gary... Is that...
不會吧。
It can't be.
我太喜歡了，真是好魔術啊。
I'm really enjoying this. It's a great trick.
蘇珊？
Susan?
-羅伯塔？
-我不敢相信。
- Roberta?
- I don't believe it.
-羅伯塔…
-加裡，坐下。
- Roberta...
- Gary, sit down.
呃，我在這兒呆會兒，謝謝。
uh... I think I'll be staying, thank you.
鼓
(drum roll)
煙，要煙嗎？
Cigars? Cigarettes?
她還是很有型的啊。
She's really got style in a way.
她很不錯啊，加裡。
She's good, Gary.
哦，對不起。
(Larry) Right. Sorry.
尖叫
(Roberta screams)
(screams)
哇哦！
Bravo!
是他，就是他。
That's him. That's the guy.
就是他！
That's the guy!
嗨，救救我。
Hey, help me!
嘿，就是他，就是他，救命。
Hey! That's the guy!
That's the guy! Help!
來人抓住他，幫幫我。
Somebody stop that guy! Help!
怎麼…羅伯塔。
What... Roberta!
-羅伯塔。
-你是誰？
- Roberta!
- Who are you?
怎麼了？
What's going on?!
-他打傷你了？我殺了他。
-加裡。
- Did he hurt you? I'll kill him!
- Gary!
-沒事了，我現在可以搞定了。
-這人是誰？
- It's OK, I can take care of it now.
- Who is this guy?
你是誰？你什麼意思，我是誰？
Who are you?
What do you mean, who am I?
-拜託…
-哦。
- Please...
- Oh.
加裡，迪茲。
Gary... Dez.
迪茲，他是加裡，我丈夫。
Dez, this is Gary, my husband.
嗨。
Hi.
-做熱水盆的生意人？
-是。
- The hot-tub salesman?
- Yeah.
這麼說你昨晚告訴我的是真的了。
So you were telling me
the truth last night.
昨晚？哦，不。
Last night? Oh, no.
-你和他過了一夜？
-加裡…
- Did you spend the night with him?
- Gary...
-他就是警察提到的拉皮條的？
-他不是拉皮條的。
- Is he the pimp the police mentioned?
- He's not a pimp!
我不是拉皮條的，我是她一個朋友。
I'm not a pimp. I'm a friend of hers.
-有誰呢能告訴我發生什麼了？
-我自己都不知道。
- Somebody tell me what's going on!
- I'm not sure myself.
-這段時間我糟糕透了…
-我也是。
- I'm having a hard time...
- So am I!
先停一停，停一停。
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Please, wait a minute, wait a minute.
聽我說。
OK, listen.
迪茲，迪茲，我需要和加裡單獨談一談，好嗎？
Dez. Dez, I really need to talk
to Gary alone, OK? Please?
好吧。
OK.
我也需要自己靜一靜。
I really need some time alone too.
對不起。
I'm sorry.
都過去了，沒事了，噩夢結束了。
It's all right. It's all right.
The nightmare's over.
彈球機
(pinball machine pinging)
別吱吱叫，你要把我帶出去。
Don't make a peep.
You're gonna get me outta here.
低叫
(Susan whimpers)
腿不錯。
Nice legs.
-我不明白你和那個傢伙為什麼會在這兒。
-你又為什麼在這兒？
- I don't understand why you're here.
- Why are you here?
等等，先別管那個，你為什麼離開我？
Wait a minute. Never mind that.
Why did you leave me?
那是某種意外的事。
It was sort of an accident.
意外？當你在拉客也是個意外了？
When you were soliciting,
that was an accident, too?
是的，當然是，加裡。
Yes, of course! Gary!
一切都是從尋人啟事開始的。
It all started with the personals.
那是給蘇珊的廣告，《不顧一切找蘇珊》。
There was this ad for Susan.
"Desperately seeking Susan."
他到哪裡去了？
Where did he go?
所以他們就認為我是個妓女而把我逮捕了。
So they thought
I was a prostitute and arrested me.
羅伯塔，你是同性戀嗎？
Roberta, are you a lesbian?
萊斯莉說很多妓女都是同性戀。
Leslie said
lots of prostitutes are lesbians.
加裡，你沒有聽我在說什麼，
我不是妓女，也不是同性戀。
Gary, you're not listening to me.
I'm not a prostitute or a lesbian!
我們需要找專業人員來幫助你，
我不管那要花多少錢。
We'll get professional help.
I don't care how much it costs.
-我只要你現在跟我回家。
-為什麼？
- I just want you to come home with me.
- Why?
為什麼？你什麼意思，為什麼？
Why? What do you mean, why?
為什麼你要我跟你一起回家？
Why do you want me
to come home with you?
拜託，別那麼激動，行嗎？
Come on, don't get excited, all right?
你是吸毒了還是吃什麼了？
What, are you on drugs
or something now?
天啊。
God.
看著我。
Look at me.
我看著呢，你看起來像個怪物。
I looked at you. You look ridiculous.
我是說看著我，加裡，看著我。
I mean look at me, Gary.
Look at me.
我不和你一起回家。
I'm not coming home with you.
你只不過是累了。
You're just tired.
為什麼你不換套衣服，然後我們在家中討論這個？
Why don't you get changed
and we'll talk about it at home?
來吧，來吧。
Come on. Come on.
很好，這很好。
Fine. That's fine.
呃，我先去外邊，我只等你五分鐘。
uh... I'm gonna go outside
and I'm gonna wait for five minutes.
如果你不過來，我就自己走了。
And if you're not there,
I'm gonna leave without you.
再見，加裡。
Goodbye, Gary.
嘿，哇！
Hey! Whoa!
你從哪裡得到的？
Where did you get this?
別動。
Stay!
蘇珊，這是怎麼回事？
Susan, what's going on?
救救我。
(whispers) Help me!
別推我。
Don't push!
動作好快，陌生人。
Good goin', stranger.
蘇珊。
Susan.
-嗨。
-笑
- Hi.
- (giggling)
怎麼了？
What's going on?
朋友們，現在是決戰時刻了。
My friend, this is the crucial moment.
我們把主力轉移到船上。
Our force field power plant
has been transferred to the ship.
我們的防線在敵人最薄弱的地方，
完全可以視實際情況而機動作戰。
Our defences are at their weakest,
almost fully automatic.
突然襲擊的成功可能性是非常大的。
The likelihood of a successful
mutant attack is at its strongest.
-並且他們可能沒有意識到。
-我們努力保持這種狀況…
- But they may be unaware.
- We've tried to keep them away...
哎呦。
Ow!
-嗨。
- Hi.
你怎麼樣了？
Huh. How are you doin'?
還行。
OK.
那麼我猜你的名字不叫蘇珊，啊？
So I guess your name isn't Susan, huh?
那麼是什麼？
So what is it?
羅伯塔。
Roberta.
-羅伯塔。
-嗯。嗯。
- Roberta.
- Mm-hm.
多好的名字。
That's nice.
多好的一對！
WHAT A PAIR!
電影下載：http://www.verycd.com/topics/2762424/
英文字幕來源：http://www.opensubtitles.org/en/
subtitles/3391468/desperately-seeking-susan-en
中文翻譯並調校：budebuai。
所用軟件：人人影視時間機器
2009年10月23日